无垠的太空
第一季 第五集
《无垠的太空》前情提要
Previously on The Expanse...
你们这群小混混 你们惹到大金主了
You gutter punks. You screwed the golden goose.
离水远点!
Stay away from the acqua!
如果是你女朋友登记了那条求救信号
If your girlfriend logged that distress call
她很长一段时间都好过不了了
she's going to be living it down for a long time.
-是我干的 -请救救我
- I did it. - Please help me.
这些都和她有关
It's all got to do with her.
你该向上级汇报
You need to take this upstairs.
也许吧 在那之前 我还是
Maybe. Until then I'll just, uh...
尽我的一点绵薄之力吧
I guess I'll do my pathetic best.
她出发前几周
Before she shipped out,
她让我帮她联系一个数据掮客
she asked me to hook her up with a data broker.
她在跟一些外行星联盟的死忠交往
She was hanging around some hardcore OPA.
安德森·道斯
Anderson Dawes.
朱莉·毛是我们的人
Julie Mao was one of ours.
她的事交给我来操心
Let me worry about her,
你去找菲拉特·科塔里
and you'll get Filat Kothari.
去伸张正义
Go get your justice.
让它更完美
Make it pretty.
我们没法辨别引擎特征
We can't resolve the drive signatures
也没法通过外形辨别船的身份
or make any visual IDs.
有人拥有了一支新的战舰部队
Somebody has a new fleet of warships.
我不是飞行员 你得找别人来驾驶这艘船
I'm not a pilot, someone else needs to fly.
我觉得我现在的状态...
I don't think I'm in any condition to...
-带我们离开! -没问题
- Get us out of here! - You got it.
准许你们进入第谷的安全港
You will be granted safe harbor on Tycho.
我郑重承诺 你们不会受到任何伤害
You have my solemn promise that you will not be harmed.
认识像他那样带着动机的人
I've known guys with causes.
会让人送命的动机
Causes that get people killed.
你不会无缘无故出现在任何地方
You don't show up anywhere without a reason.
我早就不再为你们这些人精工作了
I don't work for you fine people anymore.
那么 这次突然袭击是为了什么?
So, why am I being ambushed?
我需要借你在第谷空间站的间谍一用
I need to borrow your spy on Tycho Station.
借去做什么?
What for?
帮忙盯着点佛瑞德·约翰逊
To keep an eye on Fred Johnson.
他多收了那些摩门教徒不少钱
He's over-charging the Mormons for their toilet seats.
我不能把他借给你
Well, you can't have him.
为什么?
Why not?
我花了五年时间才让他成功潜进约翰逊的组织
It took me five years to sheep-dip him in Johnson's outfit,
为他的竞争对手盗取技术
to steal tech for his competitors.
他对我来说可是价值不菲
He's worth a lot of money to me.
什么是潜伏?
What's... sheep-dip?
我不知道小卖部有没有卖冰淇淋呢?
I wonder if they have ice cream in the snack shop?
答案是不行
The answer's no.
和佛瑞德·约翰逊过不去
I do my patriotic duty
就算完成我的爱国义务了
by screwing over Fred Johnson,
那样还不够吗?
isn't that enough?
你儿子还好吗 埃斯特本?
How's your son, Esteban?
他不久就能申请假释了
He's up for parole soon.
你真的要跟我来这一手吗?
You're really gonna play that card?
不玩花样 不找借口
No games, no subterfuge,
就这么直切要害了?
just straight for the jugular?
我很乐意改日再和你玩 卡洛斯
I'd be happy to play some other time, Carlos,
但是事情紧急
but the matter is pressing.
他犯了一个错误而已
He made one mistake...
那就帮他翻过这一页
Then help him move on.
让我来帮他
Let me help him.
你知道我为什么不干情报工作了吗?
You know why I quit the intel desk?
因为我不知道
I couldn't tell anymore
是不是还在为好人工作
if I was still working for the good guys.
我去买冰淇淋 你来打电话
I'll go get the ice cream, you make the phone call.
罗西南蒂号 你们可以在Z4船位停靠了
Rocinante, you are cleared for station dock at Berth Z4.
请关闭引擎
Please cut your engines
并将引导系统控制权移交给第谷控制中心
and release your guidance systems to Tycho TC.
收到 第谷空间站
Acknowledged, Tycho Station.
你现在已获得控制权
You now have control.
第谷空间站
小行星带
准备与泊位固定装置对接
Prepare for docking clamp capture.
詹姆斯·霍顿
James Holden.
-你个混小子 -站那别过来
- You son of a bitch... - Stay where you are.
你要么是个天才 霍顿先生
You either some kind of genius, Mr. Holden,
要么就是全太阳系最幸运的人
or you the luckiest dipshit in the solar system.
为什么邀请我们来这里?
Why did you invite us here?
你们俩是一系列
You two are the only witnesses
灾难事故仅剩的见证人
to a series of catastrophic events.
你们可能是阻止一场全面战争的关键
You could be the key to stopping all-out war.
我们不是唯一的见证人 你一直在看
We're not the only witnesses. You were watching.
我已经很久不掺和战争了 年轻人
I've been out of the war business a long time, son.
我负责为各方商定和平协议
I broker peace treaties these days...
你的名声可不是这样的
Not exactly what you're known for...
你们可以把那些枪收起来了
You can put those guns away.
叫其他人出来
Tell the others to come out.
我会给你们提供避风港
I'll give you safe harbor.
我也会为你们处理掉那艘飞船
And I'll get rid of that ship for you.
谁都不能处理掉我们的飞船
No one's getting rid of our ship.
火星船只每天都会经过第谷
Martian vessels come through Tycho on a daily basis.
如果他们看到那艘护卫舰停在那
If they see that frigate parked there,
我也吃不了兜着走
it's a bad day for me too.
我只是个信使
I'm just the messenger,
我这有半个排的气炸了的火星陆战队员
I have half a platoon of pissed-off Martian marines
等不及想以牙还牙呢
who are just itching for some payback.
轻巡洋舰级别的
That's a corvette-class
火星护卫舰一般有三十个船员
Martian frigate that typically crews thirty.
我只看到你们两个
I only see two of you.
这说明你们在努力掩饰你们的人数
That tells me that you're trying hard to hide your numbers.
战术上讲 如果你们还有更多人
Tactically, if there were more,
为了展示力量 你们一定会让他们都出来
as a show of force you would've brought them out.
所以我猜你们舰上也就剩二到四个人了
I'm guessing there are two to four people left on your ship.
我很有信心地说 舰上绝对没有什么火星军队
And I'm confident that there's no Martian Navy on board.
要是有 他们现在已经出来跟我交谈了
If they were, they'd be out here speaking with me now.
你从那艘船出来 因为你是负责的
You walked off that ship, because you're in charge.
至少你认为你是
At least you think you are...
如果我想伤害你
If I wanted to hurt you,
我会将你们的应答器代码和
I would have broadcast your transponder
位置向整个太阳系公布
and your position to the entire system...
来这里是你唯一的选择
Coming here was your only option.
但也是你最好的选择
But it was also your best option.
现在 你是想继续玩把戏
Now, you want to continue to play games,
还是我们谈谈怎么互相帮助?
or shall we talk about how to help each other?
我是丽达
I'm Lida.
这是我兄弟 开普
My brother, Kaipo.
你父母肯定很为你们骄傲吧
Your parents must be proud.
你们不能这么对他
You can't do that to him.
他是恒星螺旋警察
He's Star Helix.
我估计你也不想出名吧?
I take it then that you don't want to be famous, huh?
旧款的出舱头盔也会造成那样的烫伤
The old EVA helmets used to burn like that...
接触的地方会把皮烫掉
The contacts would cook your skin.
谢谢你的分享
Thanks for sharing.
我不得不让那个畜生科塔里走人
I had to let that stinking animal Kothari go,
反正你对他也没兴趣
since you weren't interested in him.
我们要好好谈谈了 你和我
We're going to have a nice long talk, you and I.
谈多久就看你了
How long, depends on you.
废弃的小行星矿
火星贸易区 位于小行星带
迪亚戈!
Diogo! Hey!
怎么这么久?
What's taking so long?
在安装最后一根了 马泰奥叔叔
Setting the last charge now, Uncle Mateo...
快点 否则你就回谷神星偷水去吧
Well hurry up, or you'll be back stealing water on Ceres.
你个小街鼠
You street rat.
炸药装好了吗?
Did you pattern the charges?
好了 都是按你说的来的
Yeah, yeah, just like you said...
赚钱的时候到了 小子
Time to make some money, bachemang.
双方交火后 一切都很快结束了
Once all the shooting got started, it was over pretty quick.
火星人都还没弄清是谁在攻击他们
The Martians barely knew what hit 'em.
唐纳吉尔号和坎特号是被
The Donnager and the Cant were attacked
同类隐形飞船攻击的
by the same class of stealth warships.
你得出面作证
You will have to testify.
作证?
Testify?
向联合国安理会
To the UN Security Council.
你是说你和外行星联盟不被允许进入的那个吗?
You mean the one that you and the OPA aren't allowed into?
你会为我敲开那扇门的
You'll open that door for me.
你要利用我来为你赢得那里的一席之地?
You want to use me to get yourself a seat at the table?
当马前卒没什么不好 霍顿
It's okay to be a pawn, Holden,
只要你选对了立场
so long as you're on the right side.
也许你对那些飞船的来历一清二楚
Maybe you know exactly where those ships came from.
也许我一无所知
Maybe I have no idea.
你外面造着的那艘船可不小
It's a pretty big boat you're building out there.
造一个小型隐形舰队也不是不可能
A small fleet of stealth ships wouldn't be impossible.
我不打算和你辩论
I'm not going to debate with you.
我们要回我们的飞船了
We're going back to our ship now.
恐怕你们回不去了
I'm afraid you can't go back to the ship.
看来他不喜欢说再见
Sounds like he doesn't like goodbyes.
太刀号现在归我控制了
I'm taking control of the Tachi right now.
-想得美! -不许动!
- The hell you are! - Freeze! Right there!
那些枪也帮不了你了
Those guns can't help you anymore.
你确定想试试是不是那样吗?
Are you sure you want to find out if that's true?
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
你最好往后躲躲 霍顿
You might want to don a poncho, Holden.
你最好别惹这位
You don't want to test this particular guy.
我用过埋过上百个你这种人了
I've raised and buried your kind by the hundreds.
他们不是我
Not my kind.
童年悲惨 抠扳机很快 理解事情很慢
Broken boys, quick to the trigger, slow on the uptake.
来吧 小子
Go ahead, son.
开枪 子弹会射穿我
Pull it, bullet will cut right through me,
但我身后
but there'll be countless
是无数外行星联盟的兄弟姐妹
OPA brothers and sisters standing behind me.
他们会追杀你到天涯海角
They will hunt you to the ends of the Belt.
霍顿 让屠夫命令他的人退下
Holden, tell The Butcher to call off his men,
否则我让亚历克斯把他的空间站炸个窟窿
or I'll have Alex vent his bloody station.
外面情况如何?
How's it going out there?
长官
Um, sir,
这出了点问题
we have a problem.
你在数据掮客那找到了什么?
What did you find at the data broker's place?
就一些三流黄片
Some third-rate porn.
我想你的手下 他们把好东西都拿走了
I guess your men... I think they got all the good stuff.
你回去朱莉·毛的公寓做什么?
Why did you go back to Julie Mao's apartment?
我坦白
I'm gonna come clean.
说出来有点丢脸 但是
Embarrassing... But...
我真的很喜欢她的浴室
I really like her shower.
淋浴水压太棒了
It's great water pressure.
不 别这样
Nah, hey, hey!
你为什么这么关心这女孩的去向?
Why do you care so much what happened to this girl?
我对待我的工作非常认真
I take my job... very seriously.
你是空间站里的笑话
You are the station joke.
我可是有调查过的
I did my homework.
或许吧 但恒星螺旋知道我在追查你
Maybe, but Star Helix knows I'm onto you.
所以 你要小心可别做得太过火
So... you wanna be careful how far you wanna take this.
我们本该在黑船酒吧里
Should be in the Black Freighter right now,
一起请对方喝酒 谈论未来的计划
buying each other rounds, talking future plans.
戴戴看
Try it on.
你脑袋够大
Your head's big enough.
我们可是在为可贵的事而奋斗 米勒
We are fighting for something precious here, Miller.
肯定的 更多的码头资源
Sure, a fatter percentage of the docks.
你连思维都像地球人
You even think like an Earther.
你真了不起 老兄
You are something, man.
你制造混乱 唯恐天下不乱
You create a bunch of chaos, you stir shit up
好让自己可以出来拯救世界 是吧?
so you can ride in and save the day, right?
你不知道我们离成功有多近了?
You have no idea how close we are, huh?
我说的可是独立!
I am talking about independence!
是啊 然后你当总督
Yeah. With you as governor.
这主意真好
It's a great idea.
海岩号的悲剧就是对你的警告
You know, that Scopuli disaster is a dead fish on your doorstep.
你老搞错重点!
You keep missing the point!
怪不得你要让毛的事石沉大海
That's why you gotta make the Mao case disappear.
唯一的问题是
The only question is,
你为什么要牺牲她?
why you gotta sacrifice her?
该死
Sa baka.
真不敢相信我竟然没早点看出来
I can't believe I didn't see it before.
米勒警探
Detective Miller.
你爱上朱莉·毛了
You're in love with Julie Mao.
是啊
Yeah.
可以引爆了!
Detonate already!
好了 好了
I'm ready, I'm ready.
网子锁好了吗?
You locked down the net?
是的
Yeah, yeah.
那为什么我的财产越飘越远?
Then why is my money floating away?
傻瓜!
Sabang!
没用的蠢货
Stupid, good-for-nothing rat.
那网子很旧了
The net is old.
等我们把网收好
By the time we secure the haul,
货得损失掉一半
half will be lost.
赚的钱也就够这趟的成本
I'll barely make enough to cover the trip.
兴隆号请注意 这是火星舰队大西庇阿号
Attention Xinglong, this is MCRN Scipio Africanus.
关闭引擎并做好被登船预备
Power down and prepare to be boarded.
他们要找谁?
Who they want?
明白告诉你吧
Cards are on the table.
我提供了艘船去谷神星外
I provided a ship for an OPA recon mission
执行外行星联盟的侦查任务 船失踪了
out of Ceres, which disappeared.
船的名字就是海岩号
The name of that ship is the Scopuli.
没错 我需要这艘护卫舰来寻回
That's right. I need this frigate to retrieve
唯一的生还者 莱昂内尔·波兰斯基
the lone survivor, Lionel Polanski.
-谁? -那是个代号
- Who? - It's a code name.
就在悲剧发生不久后
We received a set of coordinates from him
我们收到他传送来的一组坐标
a short time after the disaster.
他会比任何人清楚
He would know more than anyone else about
这一切的起因和背后主使
what started this and who's behind it.
你一定还有其他舰艇可派
There's got to be another ship you can send...
我需要艘战舰
I need a gunship.
外头的局势越来越紧张
It's getting hot out there.
而外行星联盟没有这种战舰
And the OPA's got nothing like this.
我会把你的特工接回来的
I'll pick up your operator.
身为目击者你太重要 万一你遇害
You're too valuable as a witness, if you get killed...
另外三个人也同样目睹了我的所见
The other three saw just as much as I did.
他们会留下来做你的证人
They'll stay and be your witnesses.
我们都会提供宣誓证词
We'll all give sworn statements.
抱歉 我没法这么做
I'm sorry. I can't do that.
我们还会相处
We're going to be spending a lot of time
很长一段时间
staring at each other across the dock out there.
你和我目标一致
You and I both want the same thing.
都是要为我们的同胞做对的事
To do right by our people.
让我去吧
Let me do this.
火星舰队大西庇阿号
火星边境巡逻队
把手举起来!
Hands where I can see them!
有运送任何武器吗?
Transporting any weapons?
没有 有什么问题吗 老大?
No, what's the problem, bosmain?
你们的应答器在哪
Show us your transponder.
已经过期了
Says here it's expired.
怎么啦 矿工骑士?
What happened, pebble jockey?
你喝高了忘记更新执照了吗?
Did you get drunk and forget to renew your license?
我没钱 朋友
I didn't have the scrip, copeng,
我得更换...
I had to replace the...
你们小行星带人总有借口
Yeah, you Belters always got an excuse.
我们必须罚你的款
We're gonna have to AO-66 you.
当你们抵达爱神星时
When you arrive on Eros,
货物会被扣留
your cargo will be held
直至你们缴清全部罚款
under lien until your fines are paid in full.
别这样 一定有其他办法...
Oh, come on, there must be something...
放开他
Hey! Leave him alone.
放松 放松 放松 放松
Dzeet! Dzeet! Dzeet! Dzeet!
何必这样呢?
Why are you doing this?
扣了我们的货你们的征税官就没钱收了
Impound our haul and there's nothing left for your taxman.
我们太为难你们了吗?
Oh, are we being too hard on you?
要不要放你们一马?
Should we cut you a break?
我们也是为了养家糊口 好吗?
We are just tryin' to feed our families, okay?
告诉你我会怎么帮你吧
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do for you...
什么也不帮
Absolutely nothing.
凭什么你们可以衣食无忧?
What God gives you the right to life's riches, huh?
你们划好区域 限制我们的航行自由
You set up your zones and tell us where we can and cannot go.
你们吃饱喝足 住着玻璃宫殿
You living belly-full, with your glass palaces,
而我的同胞有半数正在饿死
while half my people are starving to death.
这公平吗?
How is this justice?
你们小行星带人想为炸了唐纳吉尔号负责
You Skinnies wanna take credit for blowin' up the Donnager,
我们就给你公平 用我的两个拳头
we'll give you justice. With both hands.
我们拿什么去炸那么大的火星战舰?
What are we gonna blow up the big Martian warship with, huh?
小矿球?
Little pebbles?
祝你愉快
Have a nice day.
放开他 他不是那意思
Leave him alone! He didn't mean...
我刚才对你很客气了
Hey. I went easy on you before.
不过现在
But now...
你回家的时候
You're not gonna pass through
别想通过管制区域了 老大
the restricted zone on your way home, "Bosmain."
我们绕不了道 燃料不够! 会死的
We can't go around. Not enough fuel! We die for sure.
那是你的问题 不是我的
That's your problem, not mine.
你怎么知道坐标那儿有什么?
How do you know what's waiting at those coordinates?
我不知道
I don't.
佛瑞德·约翰逊也不知道
Neither does Fred Johnson.
一旦出事
And when the felotas hit the fan,
他就会跟你撇清关系
he will wipe his hands clean of you.
更何况也许这就是他下的套
That's assuming it's not a set-up in the first place.
海岩号的事他为什么要撒谎?
Why would he lie about the Scopuli?
给自己找麻烦吗?
Get himself tangled up in this mess?
你脑袋进水了
You're out of your ever-lovin' mind,
居然觉得可以相信那家伙
you think you can trust that guy.
我只答应要自己去
Look, I only committed myself.
佛瑞德·约翰逊答应给我人
Fred Johnson offered to crew me up.
你们可以安全地待在第谷直到事情平息
You guys'll be safe here on Tycho till all this blows over,
然后就可以各回各家了
then you can go back to your lives.
等等 你要用他的船员?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. You're using his crew?
你怎么知道你们出发后
How do you know he's not going to
他们不会把你扔太空里去?
space you the second you get out there?
因为你可以把罗西号设置成
Because you're going to rig the Roci
只服从我的命令
so it only responds to my command.
天啊
For God's sake.
我不必相信佛瑞德·约翰逊
Look, I don't need to trust Fred Johnson.
我们双方都拿枪指着对方的脑袋
We both have a gun to each other's head.
那这算是什么?
So, what is this?
再见?
Goodbye?
不行
Nah.
外面等着你的只会是更多麻烦
All that's waiting out there for you is more trouble,
更多死亡 你为什么这么坚决 霍顿?
More death. Why are you so hell-bent, Holden?
因为这是我的错
Because this is my fault.
什么是你的错?
What is?
坎特号收到的求救信息是我登记的
I logged the distress call on the Cant.
艾莫斯
Amos...
很高兴我们终于弄清楚了
I'm glad we cleared this up.
我是知道的
I knew.
霍顿做的是对的
Holden did the right thing.
你干嘛不告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?
我不知道
I don't know.
你害怕我
You were afraid of me.
你本该说点什么的
You shoulda said somethin'.
那么
So...
我们来谈谈朱莉·毛
Let's talk about Julie Mao.
她还活着?
Is she alive?
她选择加入外行星联盟
She chose to be OPA because she believed
因为她相信我们为正义而战
that what we are fighting for is just.
你们招了个无知少女
You took an innocent kid
还逼她替你们干脏活
and you forced her to do your dirty work.
并非如此! 她找上门来 求我帮忙
No! She came to me. Asked me to help her.
她知道自己在做什么
She knew what she was doing.
她自愿为我们做出牺牲
She was willing to make a sacrifice for us.
比你高尚多了
It's more than you.
她相信你
She trusted you,
把自己交到你手上
she put herself in your hands
是因为她没看到你的双手沾满献血
'cause she couldn't see the blood on 'em.
就像你害死你妹妹一样
Just like your sister...
对吗?
Isn't that right?
当你让她死在小行星带时
Wasn't she like 15
她好像也就十五岁吧?
when you let her die out on the Belt?
当然 这是你的传说中你想略去的那部分
Sure. It's part of the legend you like to leave out.
-这个故事人尽皆知 -我深表怀疑
- Everybody knows that story... - I doubt that.
那时你们只是蠢孩子 对吗?
You were just stupid kids, right?
在小行星带倒卖矿石
Rock-hopping out on the Belt.
然后呢
And what,
你忘记检查她的磁力靴还是什么?
you forgot to check her magboots or something?
她可是你妹妹
She was your sister.
她靠你保护她的安全
She relied on you to keep her safe.
要我告诉你真实的故事吗?
Would you like me to tell you the real story?
你肯定已经为这件事说谎无数
I'm sure you've told so many lies about it
都不记得到底发生什么吧
you don't even remember what happened.
我妹妹 雅典娜
My sister Athena
是上帝眷顾的孩子
was touched by the hand of God.
是小行星带最漂亮最聪明的孩子
The most beautiful child in all the Belt, the smartest.
但是她非常脆弱
But she was fragile.
由于生来就活在零重力的环境下
Her bones were like chalk
她的骨头就像粉笔一样
from spending a lifetime in zero-g.
她永远无法康复
She was never going to recover.
这对一个靠卖矿石为生的
An impossible burden for
贫困家庭来说是难以承受的负担
a dirt-poor family of rock-hoppers.
当她病重到不能行动时
And when she became too ill even to travel...
我还有其他三个妹妹要照顾
I had three other sisters to think about.
我们全家饥饿难耐
Our family was starving...
所以 你就杀了她
So, you killed her...
然后这就使我成了禽兽
And that makes me a monster.
当时甚至没钱安葬她
There was no scrip to bury her,
所以我就把她放在我们
so I laid her to rest
一起发现的铝土矿隧洞中 让她安息
in a beautiful bauxite tunnel that we discovered together.
你知道当你伤心欲绝时
Do you know it is possible to
真的会流出血泪吗?
cry so hard that your tears turn to blood?
背负着这样的痛苦
And living with this pain,
让我意识到了在小行星带中
I came to realize that I have millions
我有着数百万的兄弟姐妹
of brothers and sisters in the Belt.
我甚至把你也算在内
I even count you among them.
对朱莉 一个地球人也是如此
As I did Julie, an Earther.
所以每个人都为你的革命大业而死
So, everybody dies for the cause,
除了你以外
except for you.
现在我把关于朱莉的真相告诉你
Now I'll tell you the truth about Julie.
你只需要告诉我她是否还活着
Just tell me if she's alive.
如果她现在在这里
If she was here right now,
她一定会吐你一脸唾沫
she'd spit in your face.
你代表了她所鄙视的一切
You're everything she despised.
一个压迫自己族人的小行星带人
A Belter who preys on his own kind.
一个叛徒
Welwala...
就这样死去吧
Die as you lived.
谷神星上的每一滴水都曾是血和尿
That every drop of water on Ceres has been blood,
曾是眼泪和唾沫
and piss and tears and spit,
循环了上百次 还会再循环上千次
a hundred times and will be a thousand times more.
天真的地球人永远不会理解
The innocent can never comprehend this.
也许 他们会理解
Perhaps, they will comprehend the hail of stones
划破他们珍贵蓝天
that will one day come
撞击到地面的小行星的厉害的
crashing down through their precious blue skies.
你们想让我们称呼你们先生和夫人 卑躬屈膝
You want us to call you Sir and Madam, and grovel,
好像我们是二等公民一样
like we are some second-class citizens.
好吧 享受你们最后的时光吧
Well, enjoy your final days in...
繁星是属于小行星带人
...the stars belong to Belters,
天堂是属于小行星带人的
the heavens belong to Belters...
叔叔 你要干什么?
Uncle, what are you doing?
你要干什么?
What are you doing?
马泰奥叔叔 不要!
Uncle Mateo, no!
不要! 别这样!
No! No, no, no!
走! 走!
Go on! Go!
-不要! -滚出去!
- No! - Get out!
求你了! 我会更努力的!
Please! I'll try harder!
对不起 我会更努力的!
I'm sorry. I'll work harder!
求你了! 对不起!
Please! I'm sorry!
不要!
No!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
求你 叔叔 求你了!
Please. Uncle, please!
求你了!
Please!
叔叔! 求你了!
Uncle! Please!
卡洛斯·达维拉刚跟我抱怨了半小时
Carlos Davila just reamed me out for half an hour.
他只是一个普通公民 克里斯金
He's a private citizen, Chrisjen,
你不能去压榨他的人
you can't go squeezing his berries.
我只是礼貌地要求
I politely asked to
借用一下他在第谷上的间谍
borrow his spy on Tycho.
你为什么对佛瑞德·约翰逊感兴趣?
Why are you interested in Fred Johnson?
他双手沾满鲜血 想要赎罪
He has blood on his hands and wants redemption.
当地球和火星还争得你死我活时
While Earth and Mars throw sand in each other's faces,
外行星联盟就从小行星带崛起了
the OPA rises in the Belt.
第谷公司主营加速小行星自转
Tycho spins up asteroids.
而击毁唐纳吉尔号是先进的隐形战舰
The Donnager was destroyed by advanced stealth warships.
佛瑞德·约翰逊正在建造
And Fred Johnson is building
人类历史上最大的宇宙飞船
the largest spacecraft in human history.
那他得需要调动大规模的资源
He'd have to be siphoning off resources on a massive scale.
我们抓捕的外行星联盟走私犯
The OPA smuggler we captured
携带有隐形复合材料
was carrying stealth composites.
那可不是巧合
That's not a coincidence.
你是要我就此罢手吗?
Are you going to shut me down?
佛瑞德·约翰逊背弃了地球
Fred Johnson turned his back on Earth.
外行星联盟杀了你儿子
The OPA killed your son.
你确定这不是私人恩怨?
You sure this isn't personal?
还真被你说对了就是私人恩怨
You're damn right it's personal.
好吧
All right.
有消息通知我
You keep me in the loop.
当然
Of course.
我叫丹尼尔
I'm Daniel.
我没兴趣 丹尼尔
I'm not interested, Daniel.
告诉我 这的人对你怎么样?
Tell me. How do they treat you here?
其他人说这比大多数地方都好
The others say it's better than most.
朝你抛媚眼的那个铆钉男?
That bucker, ogling you?
他左边屁股上装着刀
He's packing a knife on his left hip.
谢了
Thanks.
你算什么 他们的工会代表吗?
What are you, their union rep?
我是在这种地方长大的
I grew up in places like this.
你在这地方长大的? 我没看出来
You grew up? I wouldn't have figured that.
想必很苦吧
Must've been rough.
还好
Ah, it's fine.
你一定爽得好像
I guess you must have been as happy
有俩小弟弟的狗狗一样吧?
as a puppy with two peckers, right?
我不是 不是那个意思
I didn't... I didn't mean it like that.
哪个意思?
Like what?
我还是闭嘴吧 麻烦再来两杯!
I'm going to stop talking. Two more, please!
这是正当的生存方式
It's an honest living.
比大多数的都要正当
It's more honest than most.
你可以通过他们怎么对待他们的人
And you can tell a lot about a place
来了解一个地方
by how they treat their people.
有道理
Fair enough.
你怎么不花钱找个妞?
Why don't you spend some scrip?
去吧 对你有好处
Go on, it'd be good for you.
-我不行 -得了吧
- Ah, I can't. - Oh, come on!
你又没结婚
You're not married.
何出此言?
What makes you say that?
我说过 我在这种地方长大的
Like I said, I grew up in places like this.
我结过婚
I was married.
奔波在外 我唯一的想法就是回家
Out on a run, all I could think about was getting back home.
躺在我的床上 我脑子里梦得全是
And lying in my bed, all I could dream about
回到这里
was getting back out here.
我在火星舰队的上级说我缺乏能力
Big brass said I didn't have what it takes to
驾驶他们那酷炫的炮舰
fly their badass gun-ships...
可我告诉你 之前驾驶罗西南蒂号
But I'll tell you one thing, flying the Rocinante back there,
那是我经历过的最棒的体验了
that was just about the best feeling I have ever had.
我来弄
I'll do it.
这船会看起来像一艘不起眼的气体运输舰
The ship will look like a run-of-the-mill gas freighter.
别飞太近 也别主动避开
Don't fly too close, but don't try to avoid it.
火星巡逻队不会多看你一眼的
The Martian patrols won't give you a second look.
-引擎特征呢? -我们也正在换
- The drive signature? - We're altering that too.
为了送我们上这艘船 很多火星人牺牲了
A lot of Martians gave their lives getting us onto this ship.
战事正酣时
In the heat of the battle...
他们为了让你们离开唐纳吉尔号而拼死战斗?
they fought to get you off the Donnager?
有需要我们处理的尸体吗?
Are there any bodies we need to take care of?
洛佩兹上尉 在后面的货舱里
Lieutenant Lopez. He's in the rear hold.
他是为我们而死的
He died for us.
我会确保把他的尸体送回火星
I'll make sure his body is returned to Mars.
-他是位真正的战士 -谢谢你
- He's a fellow soldier. - Thank you.
你没事吧?
You all right?
放轻松 你设好保险了吧?
Relax. You rigged the fail-safe, right?
如果有人企图进入不该进入的区域
They try to access any areas that they shouldn't,
罗西号的核心就会自我毁灭
and the Roci's core will self-destruct.
我相信你会保护好我们的
I'm confident you got us covered.
你有信心吗?
You feeling confident?
好了 让他们去弄吧
Come on, let's let them do their thing
我们去船员休息室喝一杯
and we'll go get a drink in the crew lounge.
你确定?
You sure?
我可想喝一杯
I could use a drink.
咱们可以算在佛瑞德账上
We'll charge it to Fred's tab.
马泰奥叔叔! 求你了!
Uncle Mateo! Please!
你不用这样!
You don't need to do this!
是该有人站出来了
A man's gotta stand up.
马泰奥叔叔!
Uncle Mateo!
该有人站出来了!
A man has got to stand up!
快回来!
Come back!
我们会没事的
We'll be okay.
被人踩着脖子
We can only live so long...
我们也就只能活这么久了!
with a boot to our necks!
马蒂奥叔叔!
Uncle Mateo!
你没必要这样做! 我们会没事的!
You don't need to do this! We'll be okay!
兴隆号 你在非法截击航线上
Xinglong, you are on unauthorized intercept course.
-立刻调整轨道 -没关系的 迪奥戈
- Adjust trajectory immediately... - It's okay, Diogo.
-会有人找到你的 -我们会没事的!
- Someone will find you out there. - We'll be okay!
终有一天 世界会改变的
Someday, things gonna change.
我们会没事的 叔叔 我们会没事的!
We'll be okay, Uncle. We'll be okay!
该有人站出来了
A man's gotta stand up.
敬谢德
To Shed.
总是那么慷慨
Always generous.
体贴
Thoughtful...
有时又是个爱发牢骚的小刺儿头
Sometimes, a whiny little prick.
我们会想念你的 伙计
We're going to miss you, pal.
无论你在哪
Wherever you are,
我希望那里没有人需要看医生
I hope no one there needs medical attention.
干杯!
Yam seng!
敬那些让我们逃离唐纳吉尔号的勇敢的疯子们
To those brave, crazy bastards who got us off the Donnager.
拿出点敬意嘛
A little respect.
我心中充满敬意
I have nothing but respect.
那你在想什么?
Then what's your problem?
那些工和的军人被一个穿制服的
Gung-ho military hypnotized by a uniform,
狂热的,虔诚的疯子催眠了
fanatics, religious freaks.
那些火星陆战队本来可以
Those Marines could've saved themselves,
拯救自己 安全回家
gone home to their families,
而不是回来救我们
instead of coming back for us.
是啊
Yeah.
那的确需要一些说服力...
Well, it did take some convincing...
我知道这都是因为你
I know it was because of you.
你为什么要回来找我们?
Why did you come back for us?
你们是因为我才会才那里
Well, you were only there because of me.
怎么?
Why?
你会为我回来吗?
Would you have come back for me?
在那个时候? 枪林弹雨的?
At the time? With all those bullets flying?
可能不会
Probably not.
等这些都结束以后
So, what's next for Naomi Nagata?
奈奥米·永田接下来要做些什么呢?
When all this blows over?
不想这个
Nawe Nada.
我正用我幸存的脑细胞
I'm using my last remaining brain cells,
试图杀死我最后的脑细胞
to try and kill my last remaining brain cells.
咱们就这么干吧?
So let's get to work on that, shall we?
我来吧
I got it.
我以前从没杀过人
I never killed anyone before.
好的
Right...
你会没事的
You'll be all right.
我要吐了
I'm gonna be sick.
你会没事的
Hey, you're all right.
只是正常反应
It's just a reaction.
我工作的第三年
You know, my third year on the job,
我抓到个小行星带人
I caught this Skinny,
他来自下层
he was from the Lower Levels.
那时他从一个吸毒窝点出来
He was coming out of a drug-den,
抓着他老妈的头发
he grabbed his old lady by the hair,
挥舞着他的武器
he was waving his piece around.
喝吧
Drink.
然后
And, um...
他知道他们是怎么说的
You know how they tell you in basic,
你要么会开枪 要么不开枪
you're either somebody who can pull the trigger or you ain't.
好吧
Well,
你我都一样
you and me are the same.
第一次开枪
First shot,
我杀了他
I killed him, all right.
触动我的并不是血或是枪火味
But it wasn't the blood or the iron smell of it that got me.
而是窗前的一个小姑娘
It was that little girl in the window,
她看着我
watching me.
你懂得
You know...
他是我唯一杀过的人
The only guy I ever killed...
每次你回忆一件事
You know, every time you remember something,
你的脑子就会改变它 就改一点儿
your mind changes it, just a little,
直到它变成最好的和最糟糕的记忆
until your best and your worst memories,
它们是你最大的幻觉
they're your biggest illusions.
我的建议是忘记它
My advice is just forget it.
让你自己忘记
Make yourself forget it.
谢谢
I appreciate that,
但真是个糟糕的主意
but it's terrible advice.
也许吧
Yeah, probably.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
在朱莉家找到的
Found this at Julie's.
看看里面有什么
Let's see what's on it.
你来晚了
You're late.
-这是怎么回事? -就不用向我们发表演讲了
- What is this? - Oh, spare us the speech.
飞船准备好了
The ship's ready.
你准备好了吗?
Are you?
看来艾莫斯要错过了
I guess we lost Amos.
他一会就来
Oh, he'll be here in a sec.
好
Okay.
我去冲几杯咖啡
I guess I'll put on some coffee.
你们真会讨价还价
You people drive a hard bargain.
你已经拿到我们录好的声明了
You got our recorded statements.
如果莱昂内尔·波兰斯基在那里
We'll bring your Lionel Polanski home,
我们会把他带回来的
if he's out there.
作为交换 我要你帮我找一个人
In return, I want you to help me find someone.
有朝一日 我会告诉你名字的
Someday, I'll come to you with a name.
不许提问
No questions asked.
我会竭尽所能
I'll do what I can.
天呐 米勒 我还该问吗?
Jesus, Miller. Should I even ask?
我弄明白了
I figured it out...
绝大部分吧
Most of it, anyway.
看
Here...
这东西不是休眠状态 它正在散发热量
It's not dormant, it's giving off heat.
我看到分子反应
I'm seeing molecular reactions...
振动共鸣贯穿光谱
Vibrational resonances all across the spectrum...
你们能听到我说话吗?
Can you hear me?
看看这东西
Look at this thing.
我到底在看什么?
What the hell am I looking at?
你在看 我不知道 某种生物武器?
You're looking at, I don't know, some kind of bio-weapon?
这段视频是从哪来的?
Where'd this recording come from?
土卫九 我是这么认为的
Phoebe, that's what I think.
-土卫九空间站 -我是说你从来弄来的?
- Phoebe Station. - I meant where'd you get it?
朱莉·毛那里
Julie Mao.
她从一个数据掮客那买来的
She bought that from a data-broker.
她把视频交给了道斯
She gave it to Dawes.
道斯对这艘非法飞船做了手脚
Dawes screwed up this black-bag ship
船和船上的人全都消失了
which vanishes with all souls aboard.
然后数据掮客死了
And then, the data-broker ends up dead,
飞船开始爆炸
and ships start blowing up.
我们知道幕后黑手是谁吗?
We know who's pulling the strings?
来分析一下
Well, let's play it through.
土卫九上的科学家发现了什么
Scientists on Phoebe discover something,
某种足以改变权力平衡的重要物质
something big that would tip the balance of power.
外行星联盟听到风声 派了一队人去偷
The OPA gets wind of it, they send a crew out to steal it.
结果任务失败
The mission goes south.
这给了某人很多权力
Which leaves someone with a lot of power,
很多资源 而此人会尽全力保守秘密
a lot of resources, who'll do anything to keep it quiet.
包括发动一场战争
Including starting a war.
而那个人掌握着这一切的关键
And that man... he holds the key.
辐射水平爆表了...
Radiation levels are off the charts...
我们已经准备好进入下一个阶段
we're ready for the next phase.
我们需要拿样品离开土卫九
We need to get a sample off Phoebe,
马上!
now!
你和任何人提过这件事吗?
You tell anyone about this?
没 只有你
No. Just you.
那这视频呢? 有复制过吗?
What about this? Copies?
没有 这是加密的
No. It's encrypted.
无法复制
You can't copy it.
删除米勒警探的档案
Erase Detective Miller's case files
取消他所有的许可
and cancel all his clearances.
已删除所有的文件
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
你被解雇了
You're fired.
道斯
Dawes...
他买通了你
he bought you.
出去
Get out.
你在为他效力
You're in his pocket.
怎么 他给自己买下了整个警队吗?
What, did he buy himself a whole police force?
随你怎么说
Have it your way.
保安
Security.
这些日子都是什么当道? 不朽的忠诚呢?
What does it go for these days, huh? Undying loyalty?
我厌倦了和一个孩子说话
I'm tired of speaking to a child.
我还厌倦闻到这股臭屎呢
Yeah, well, I'm tired of smelling this shit.
知道吗?
You know that?
送米勒先生出去
Help Mr. Miller find the door.
如果他找你麻烦 你可以开枪
If he gives you any problems, feel free to shoot him.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thanks.
第谷控制中心
Tycho Control,
这里是罗西南蒂号气体运输舰
this is gas-freighter Rocinante
请求出发许可
requesting clearance for departure.
明白 罗西南蒂号
Understood, Rocinante,
你们的飞行计划已登记
your flight plan has been filed and logged.
请注意 你们将会经过三个火星贸易区
Be advised you'll be crossing three Martian trade zones.
遭遇火星巡逻舰队的几率很高
Likelihood of encountering MCRN patrols is high.
抱歉 我们已经尽力而为
Sorry, that's the best we could do.
你们可以出发了
You are clear to disengage.
谢谢你了 伙计
Thank you kindly, partner.